Wonder by RJ palaso lamb to the slaughter LIKE A LAMB to the slaughter”: Something that you say
about someone who goes somewhere calmly, not knowing that something unpleasant is
going to happen to them I Googled it last night. That’s what I was thinking
when Miss Bosa called my name and suddenly it was my turn to talk. “My name
is August,” I said, and yeah, I kind of mumbled it. “What?” said someone. “Can you
speak up, honey?” said Miss Bosa My name is August,” I said louder,
forcing myself to look up. “I, um have a sister named Via and a dog named Daisy.
And, um that’s it.” “Wonderful,” said Miss pza Anyone have questions for August?” No one said
anything. “Okay, you’re next,” said Miss pza to Jack. “Wait, I have a question for
August,” said Julian, raising his hand. “Why do you have that tiny braid in the back
of your hair? Is that like a Padawan thing?” “Yeah a shrug nodded What’s a
Padawan thing?” said Miss pza smiling at me. “It’s from Star Wars answered Julian. “A
Padawan is a Jedi apprentice.” “Oh, interesting,” answered miss
pza looking at me. “So, are you into Star Wars August?” “I guess.” I nodded, not looking up
because what I really wanted was to just slide under the desk. “Who’s your favorite
character?” Julian asked. I started thinking maybe he wasn’t so bad. “Jango Fett.”
“What about Darth cidus he said. “Do you like him?” “Okay, guys, you can talk about Star
Wars stuff at recess,” said Miss poosa cheerfully. “But let’s keep going. We
haven’t heard from you yet,” she said to
Jack. Now it was Jack’s turn to talk, but
I admit I didn’t hear a word he said.
Maybe no one got the Darth cious thing, and maybe Julian didn’t mean anything at
all. But in Star Wars Episode three Revenge of the Sith dark cidus face gets
burned by Sith lightning and becomes totally deformed. His skin gets all
shriveled up and his whole face just kind of melts. I peaked at Julian and he
was looking at me. Yeah, he knew what he was saying choose kind THERE WAS A lot of
shuffling around when the bell rang and everybody got up to leave. I checked my
schedule and it said my next class was English, room
321. I didn’t stop to see if anyone else
from my home room was going my way: I just zoomed out of the class and down
the hall and sat down as far from the front as possible. The teacher, a really
tall man with a yellow beard, was writing on the chalkboard. Kids came in laughing and
talking in little groups but I didn’t look up. Basically, the same thing that
happened in Home Room happened again: no one sat next to me except for Jack, who
was joking around with some kids who weren’t in our home room I could tell
Jack was the kind of kid other kids like.
He had a lot of friends. He made people laugh. When the second bell rang, everyone
got quiet and the teacher turned around and faced us. He said his name was Mr
Brown and then he started talking about what we would be doing this semester. At
a certain point, somewhere between A Wrinkle in Time and shin of the Sea
he noticed me but kept right on talking.
I was mostly doodling in my notebook while he talked, but every once in a
while I would sneak a look at the other students. Charlotte was in this class. So
were Julian and Henry. Miles wasn’t. Mr Brown had written on the chalkboard in
big block letters p r e c p Okay, everybody write this down at the very
top of the first page of your English notebook.” As we did what he told us to do,
he said: “Okay, so who can tell me what a precept is? Does anyone know?” No one
raised their hands. Mr Brown smiled, nodded, and turned around to write on the
chalkboard again: PRECEPTS equal RULES ABOUT REALLY IMPORTANT THINGS! “Like a
motto?” someone called out. “Like a motto!” said Mr Brown nodding as he continued
writing on the board. “Like a famous quote.
Like a line from a fortune cookie. Any saying or ground rule that can motivate
you. Basically, a precept is anything that helps guide us when making decisions
about really important things.” He wrote all that on the chalkboard and then
turned around and faced us. “So, what are some really important things?” he asked us.
A few kids raised their hands, and as he pointed at them, they gave their answers,
which he wrote on the chalkboard in really, really sloppy handwriting: RULES.
SCHOOLWORK. HOMEWORK. “What else?” he said as he wrote, not even turning around. “Just
call things out!” He wrote everything everyone called out. FAMILY. PARENTS. PETS.
One girl called out: “The environment!” THE ENVIRONMENT, he wrote on
the chalkboard, and added: OUR WORLD!
“Sharks, because they eat dead things in the ocean!” said one of the boys, a kid
named Reed and Mr Brown wrote down SHARKS “Bees seat belts Recycling
RS Okay,” said Mr Brown writing all of those things down. He turned around when
he finished writing to face us again. “But no one’s named the most important thing
of all.” We all looked at him, out of ideas.
“God?” said one kid, and I could tell that even though Mr Brown wrote “God” down, that
wasn’t the answer he was looking for.
Without saying anything else, he wrote down: WHO WE ARE! “Who we are,” he said,
underlining each word as he said it. “Who we are! Us! Right? What kind of people are
we? What kind of person are you? Isn’t that the most important thing of all?
Isn’t that the kind of question we should be asking ourselves all the time?
“What kind of person am I? “Did anyone happen to notice the plaque next to the
door of this school? Anyone read what it says? Anyone?” He looked around but no one
knew the answer. “It says: ‘Know Thyself,’” he said, smiling and nodding. “And learning
who you are is what you’re here to do.” “I thought we were here to learn English,”
Jack cracked, which made everyone laugh.
“Oh yeah, and that, too!” Mr Brown answered, which I thought was very cool of him. He
turned around and wrote in big huge block letters that spread all the way
across the chalkboard: MR Brown SEPTEMBER PRECEPT: WHEN GIVEN THE CHOICE BETWEEN
BEING RIGHT OR BEING KIND, CHOOSE KIND lunch VIA HAD WARNED me about lunch in
middle school, so I guess I should have known it would be hard. I just hadn’t
expected it to be this hard. Basically, all the kids from all the fifth grade
classes poured into the cafeteria at the same time, talking loudly and bumping
into one another while they ran to different tables. One of the lunchroom
teachers said something about no seat saving allowed, but I didn’t know what
she meant and maybe no one else did, either, because just about everybody was
saving seats for their friends. I tried to sit down at one table, but the kid in
the next chair said, “Oh, sorry, but somebody else is sitting here.” So I moved
to an empty table and just waited for everyone to finish stampeding and the
lunchroom teacher to tell us what to do next. As she started telling us the
cafeteria rules, I looked around to see where Jack Will was sitting, but I didn’t
see him on my side of the room. Kids were still coming in as their teachers
started calling the first few tables to get their trays and stand on line at the
counter. Julian, Henry, and Miles were sitting at a table toward the back of the
room. Mom had packed me a cheese sandwich, graham crackers, and a juice box, so I
didn’t need to stand online when my table was called. Instead, I just
concentrated on opening my backpack, pulling out my lunch bag, and slowly
opening the aluminum foil wrapping of my sandwich. I could tell I was being stared
at without even looking up. I knew that people were nudging each other, watching
me out of the corners of their eyes. I thought I was used to those kinds of
stairs by now, but I guess I wasn’t. There
was one table of girls that I knew were whispering about me because they were
talking behind their hands. Their eyes and whispers kept bouncing over to me. I
hate the way I eat. I know how weird it
looks. I had a surgery to fix my cleft pallet when I was a baby, and then a
second cff surgery when I was four, but I still have a hole in the roof of my
mouth. And even though I had jaw alignment surgery a few years ago, I have
to chew food in the front of my mouth. I didn’t even realize how this looked
until I was at a birthday party once, and one of the kids told the mom of the
birthday boy he didn’t want to sit next to me because I was too messy with all
the food crumbs shooting out of my mouth.
I know the kid wasn’t trying to be mean,
but he he got in big trouble later, and his mom called my mom that night to
apologize. When I got home from the party, I went to the bathroom mirror and
started eating a saltine cracker to see what I looked like when I was chewing.
The kid was right. I eat like a tortoise, if you’ve ever seen a tortoise
eating. Like some prehistoric swamp thing the summer table HEY, IS THIS seat
taken?” I looked up, and a girl I never never saw before was standing across
from my table with a lunch tray full of food. She had long wavy brown hair, and
wore a brown T-shirt with a purple pie sign on it. “Uh, no,” I said. She put her
lunch tray on the table, plopped her backpack on the floor, and sat down
across from me. She started to eat the mac and cheese on her plate GH she said
after swallowing the first bite. “I should have brought a sandwich like you did.” “Yeah,”
I said, nodding. “My name is Summer, by the way. What’s yours?” “August.” “Cool,” she said.
“Summer!” Another girl came over to the table carrying a tray. “Why are you
sitting here? Come back to the table.” “It was too crowded,” Summer answered Come sit
here. There’s more room.” The other girl looked confused for a second. I realized
she had been one of the girls I had caught looking at me just a few minutes
earlier handcuffed over her mouth, whispering. I guess Summer had been one
of the girls at that table, too. “Never mind,” said the girl, leaving.
Summer looked at me shrug smiled and took another bite of her mac and cheese.
“Hey, our names kind of match,” she said as she chewed. I guess she could tell I
didn’t know what she meant. “Summer? August?” she said, smiling, her eyes opened wide, as
she waited for me to get it. “Oh, yeah,” I
said after a second. “We can make this the ‘summer only’ lunch table,” she said. “Only
kids with summer names can sit here.
Let’s see, is there anyone here named June or July?” “There’s aaya I said.
“Technically, May is spring,” Summer answered, “but if she wanted to sit here,
we could make an exception.” She said it as if she’d actually thought the whole
thing through. “There’s Julian. That’s like named Julia, which comes from July.” I didn’t say
anything. “There’s a kid named Reed in my English class,” I said. “Yeah, I know Reed
but how is Reed a summer name?” she asked. “I don’t know.” I shrugged. “I just
picture, like, a re of grass being a summer thing.” “Yeah, okay.” She nodded,
pulling out her notebook. “And Miss pza could sit here, too. That kind of sounds
like the word ‘petal,’ which I think of as a summer thing, too.” “I have her for home
room I said. “I have her for math,” she answered, making a face. She started writing the
list of names on the second to last page of her notebook. “So, who else?” she said. By
the end of lunch, we had come up with a whole list of names of kids and teachers
who could sit at our table if they wanted. Most of the names weren’t
actually summer names, but they were names that had some kind of connection
to summer. I even found a way of making Jack Will’s name work by pointing out
that you could turn his name into a sentence about summer, like “Jack will go
to the beach,” which Summer agreed worked fine. “But if someone doesn’t have a
summer name and wants to sit with us,” she said very seriously, “we’ll still let them
if they’re nice, okay?” “Okay.” I nodded. “Even if it’s a winter name.”
“Cool beans,” she answered, giving me a thumbs up Summer looked like her name.
She had a tan, and her eyes were green like a leaf
[Music]